Kamlesh Pandey

kpandey@ncsu.edu | +1 (984) 810-9759 | Raleigh, 27606 | LinkedIn | Website

SUMMARY

Master student at North Carolina State University, planning to concentrate on optimization modeling and data science. Skilled in Python, TensorFlow, R with work experience of six years as Supply chain planner and optimization analyst. Actively looking for Summer 2022 internships.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Industrial Engineering

North Carolina State University, Raleigh

Aug 2021 – May 2023 GPA-3.11/4.0

Bachelor of Technology, Mechanical Engineering

Dehradun Institute of Technology, Dehradun

Aug 2011 - May 2015 Percentage: 75.5/100

EXPERIENCE

Supply Chain Optimization Analyst, NewAge Product Designs Private Limited

Feb 2021 - Aug 2021

- Prepared optimal container loading plans in Cubmaster solver to maximize space utilization, saving an average of two 40" HQ containers each month
- Identified potential stock issues in advance at 13 distribution centers across the USA and Canada and prioritized inbound shipment accordingly
- Maintained Item Master Data / Product Specification database of Non-Garage SKUs by achieving more than 90% accuracy in database
- Monitored inventory level at 13 distribution centers and flagged overstock, out-of-stock, and slow-moving inventory
- Audited inventory movement of Non-Garage SKUs at the warehouse and compared with SAP system

Supply Chain Planning Manager, Reliance Industries Limited, Mumbai

Jun 2015 - Feb 2021

- Served as a logistic planner & scheduler of oil tanker loads across all RIL's rail and coastal terminals with daily product sale of 190 TKL
- Over 90% database accuracy of five oil marketing companies' customer master database.
- Configured Trading locations / dispatch units including vendor creation, product configuration, and plant creation, currently strategic 44 active trading locations pan India.
- Provided master data management (MDM), Inventory Management, and material requirement planning services to five government and private companies.
- Averaged 70 rail rakes / 180 TKL product movement per month from Jamnagar refinery to three hinterland rail terminals
- Delivered purchase requisition orders for 44 active dispatch units fortnightly basis using SAP MM module, average 90-100 TKL purchase per month

PROJECT

Vessel Scheduling Model with Profit Point (Aspen Technology Partner)

~RIL'18

• Worked with the Analytical team of Profit Point for coastal scheduling model for an optimized loading plan for 90 to 120 forward days

Rail Planning & Scheduling Model (What's Best Solver)

~*RIL'18*

Optimization model for product movement via rakes, generating optimized wagon and plant combination as a
decision variable for meeting all constraints at three rail terminals

Pan India BSIV to BSVI conversion

~*RIL* '2

• Operational planning and scheduling for pan India BSIV to BSVI conversion of rail gantry, retail outlets, and dispatch units.

(Reliance BP Mobility Limited) Company Configuration

~*RIL'20*

• Created customer master database of approx. 1400 retail outlets of RBML (British Petroleum and RIL joint venture) company in RIL's SAP system

Terminal SAP integration

~*RIL'17*

• Integration of oil tankers loading process from the terminal with the SAP team, provided FIORI based web app for online indent creation and tracking of Tank truck, led to cycle time reduction and reduction of manual labor.

Leaf Diseases Classification Using TensorFlow

~ Fall'21

• Machine leaning model to predict class of a test image out of four disease class using pretrained neural network models in TensorFlow

SKILLS

Software: Microsoft Excel | Excel Analysis | Python | TensorFlow | Scikit-learn | Pandas | NumPy | Matplotlib | Julia **Professional**: Supply Chain Planning | Freight Management | Demand Planning | Purchase Requisition | RailScheduling | Customer Service | Container optimization | Customer Service | SAP | Demand Planning | Purchasing